A Guide to the Papers of Claude Moore, 1890-2006
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Postcard from Martha B. to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 August 19, 1 postcard with ANS. (Box-folder 02-027)
  Martha is on a 1040 mile trip.
- Statement from William F. Hatcher, M.D. for Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 September 27, 1 account statement, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-028)
  The professional service fee is $2.50.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 October 7, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-029)
  Moore plans a trip to Roanoke and expects his mother to return to D. C. with him.
- Statement from William F. Hatcher, M.D. for Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 October 30, 2 account statements, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-030)
- Christmas card from Martha and David Boyes ca. 1947 December, 1 card with ANS. (Box-folder 02-031)
- Christmas card from David H. Boyes to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1947 December, 1 card. (Box-folder 02-032)
- Christmas card from Shirley and Ed Schuffman to Mrs. and Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 December 16, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-033)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 December 16, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope, 1 order form. (Box-folder 02-034)
  Moore will be home for Christmas; wants to know if she would like to return to D.C. with him; and sends a check for $100, but might ask for the unspent balance.
- Christmas card from Frank and Nannie to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 December 18, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-035)
- Letter from Margaret A. Bauer to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 January 2, 1 ALS 3pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-036)
  Margaret thanks Mrs. Moore for her hospitality and describes the trip home and a new years party and day.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 January 22, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-037)
  Moore asks if his mother is thinking of visiting and says that Rita is busy with a mass x-ray survey of Arlington County.
- Letter from Martha B. to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 February 10, 1 ALS 2pp. (Box-folder 02-038)
  Martha has moved to Iowa and misses her former neighbors in Roanoke.
- Valentine card from David Boyes to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 February 11, 1 card with ANS, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-039)
- Envelope addressed to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 February 13, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-040)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 February 21, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-041)
  Moore describes his trip to Miami and Homestead, Florida as he heads for Key West.
- Mother's Day card from David Boyes ca. 1948 May, 1 card with ANS. (Box-folder 02-042)
- Postcard from Shirley Schuffman to Katherine Moore 1948 June 14, 1 postcard with ANS. (Box-folder 02-043)
- Postcard from Helen to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1948 September 15, 1 postcard. (Box-folder 02-044)
- Letter from Helen to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1949 January 6, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-045)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore, folks, and Edith 1949 April 11, 1 ALS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-046)
  Moore has made copies of Rita's letters to share and suggests that Edith write.
- Letter from Cornilia Moore to Claude Moore 1950 June 23, 1 TL with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-047)
  Moore's aunt writes about family members.
- Life and career of Claude Moore, M.D. Interview by Charles E. Moran, Jr. 1977 April 14, 1 TD (Box-folder 02-047.5)
  These are notes from Moore's interview with a particular emphasis on his years as a student at the UVa SOM.
- Letter from Frank R. Wolf to Dr. Claude Moore and letter from Ronald Reagan to Dr. Moore 1982, October 21 and 1982 November 22, 2 TDs, 2 envelopes (Box-folder 02-047.8)
  The letter from Wolf from the U.S. House of Representatives wishes Dr. Moore a happy 90th birthday and thanks him for his support of The Claude Moore Colonial Farm at Turkey Run. The letter from President Reagan wishes Dr. Moore congratulations on his 90th birthday.
- Check from Norfolk Southern Corp. to Claude Moore 1987 June 6, 1 check, 1 brochure 12pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-048)
  The uncashed dividend check is for $56.70.
- Check from Singer Company to Claude Moore 1987 June 15, 1 check, 1 postcard, 1 notice, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-049)
  The uncashed dividend check is for $101.25.
- Ticket for dry cleaning N.D., 1 ticket. (Box-folder 02-050)
- Invoice for Dr. Claude Moore collection 2006 September 18, 1 TD 1p. (Box-folder 02-051)
- Biographies of Claude Moore and description of Lanesmoore 2006 December 5, 3 internet documents 5pp. (Box-folder 02-052)
- Biographic information obtained in conversation with Dr. Claude Moore 1973, June 9, 1TD, 2 pp., 1 photo (copy) (Box-folder 02-053)
  Conversation took place at Moore's farm near Sterling, Virginia between Moore and Marguerite Tise who wrote "The Peterman Family" which includes genealogical information about Moore's family. The photo is of the five Moore children.
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook front cover N.D., 2 photos. (Box-folder 03-001 [oversize])
  Claude Moore
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook pages 1-10 1918-19, 34 TD. (Box-folder 03-002 [oversize])
  Orders related to Moore's military service
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook pages 11-12 N.D., 1918-19, 1983, 3 photos, 1 poster. (Box-folder 03-003 [oversize])
  Includes an undated photo of Sister Edith Moore and a 1918-19 photo of Base Hospital 88
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 13 1977 November 4, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-004 [oversize])
  Claude Moore shaking hands with UVa President Frank L. Hereford; unidentified people
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 14 1977 November 4, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-005 [oversize])
  Claude Moore and UVa President Frank L. Hereford
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook pages 15-16 N.D., 1915, 3 photos, 2 newspaper clippings, 4 journal clippings. (Box-folder 03-006 [oversize])
  one of the photos is of Moore dressed for football; another is the UVa School of Medicine Class of 1960; another includes Moore, Alice Starr or Stark and Charles and Lynda Robb. Charles Robb was governor of Virginia from 1982 to 1986 and a U.S. Senator from Virginia from 1989 to 2001.
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 17 1970 June 6, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-007 [oversize])
  Claude Moore and unidentified man
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 18 1977 November 4, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-008 [oversize])
  Claude Moore and unidentified men
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 19 1979 January 12, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-009 [oversize])
  Claude Moore and Wilhelm Moll
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 20 1979 January 13, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-010 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 21 1979 January 13, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-011 [oversize])
  Claude Moore and unidentified woman
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 22 1979 May 11, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-012 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 23 1979 May 11, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-013 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 24 1979 May 11, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-014 [oversize])
  unidentified people
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 25 1979 May 11, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-015 [oversize])
  Claude Moore, James Watt and unidentified man
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 26 1979 May 11, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-016 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 27 1980 May 10, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-017 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 28 1981 January 9, B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-018 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 29 N.D., B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-019 [oversize])
  Claude Moore and unidentified people
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 30 N.D., B&W 8x10 photo. (Box-folder 03-020 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 31 1982 October 15, certificate. (Box-folder 03-021 [oversize])
  Certificate accompanied a flag that flew over the U.S. Capitol building.
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 32 N.D., color 5x7 photo. (Box-folder 03-022 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook pages 33-40 N.D., 1916, 1989 Fall Winter, 12 photos, 5 journal clippings. (Box-folder 03-023 [oversize])
  Includes photo of 1916 Erskine College, probably the football team
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook pages 41-46 N.D., 9 photos, 1 journal clipping, 1 brochure. (Box-folder 03-024 [oversize])
  Includes photo of R.D. Carmen
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook page 47 N.D., photo (Box-folder 03-025 [oversize])
  R.D. Carmen
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook pages 48-55 N.D., 1985 January 12, 13 photos, 11 journal clippings, 2 brochures. (Box-folder 03-026 [oversize])
- Claude Moore photo album/scrapbook back cover N.D., 1 photo, 2 journal clippings. (Box-folder 03-027 [oversize])
- Claude D. Moore diploma from Roanoke City High School 1911 May 18, diploma, signed (Box-folder 03-028 [oversize])
  This is the only document in the collection that gives a middle initial for Claude Moore.
- Claude Moore certificate from Roanoke College 1912 June 12, certificate, signed with AN (Box-folder 03-029 [oversize])
  Moore earned an average grade of 93.27 on his final report and was entitled to Second Distinction. A note indicates that he was a regular player on the football and baseball teams plus was offered an instructorship in chemistry for the following year which he declined because he entered the UVa School of Medicine.
- Claude Moore diploma from UVa for doctor of Medicine degree 1916 June 14, diploma, signed (Box-folder 03-030 [oversize])
- Claude Moore appointed 1st Lieutenant in the Medical Section of the Officers' Reserve Corps of the Army of the United States 1918 January 17, certificate, signed (Box-folder 03-031 [oversize])
- Claude Moore certificate from the New York Hospital 1918 August 29, certificate, signed (Box-folder 03-032 [oversize])
  The certificate indicates Moore had served as a Junior and Senior Assistant Physician and Surgeon for one year and was then appointed House Physician and House Surgeon at the House of Relief, known as the "Hudson Street Hospital."
- "Loudoun Times Mirror," "Laneville: Site of Historic Post Office" 1978 May 4, newspaper clipping with AN (Box-folder 03-033 [oversize])
  The article describes and give a history of Moore's house. It includes a picture. An annotation was added by Moore.
- Claude Moore recognized for over 50 years of service to UVa, the School of Medicine and the Medical Alumni Association 1981 May 8, certificate, signed (Box-folder 03-034 [oversize])
- Claude Moore certificate of Appreciation from the County of Fairfax for his interest in the Turkey Run Farm 1982 June 7, certificate, signed (Box-folder 03-035 [oversize])
- Claude Moore commissioned as a Kentucky colonel by the state of Kentucky 1986 September 26, certificate, signed (Box-folder 03-036 [oversize])
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 1 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: cover and 2 pages (Box-folder 04-001)
  University of Virginia vs. Georgia football
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 2 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 12 pages (Box-folder 04-002)
  Includes photos of UVa and Claude Moore and photos marked Horton Home; Dad Nov. 1891; Dr. Moore's sister Edith; William;, G. G. 1890?: Grandfather, Grandmother Horton, William? (Peterson); Helen; Dr. Moore's yacht on the Potomac R.; John H., Dad, 1900; Floyd courthouse, Woodrow Wilson Inauguration, 1913; Lesters, 1904; Michael and Shirley smiley (nephew and niece of Dr. Moore--sister Helen's children); William Peterman; Vincent, Mabel, William, Louise Horton; Barkley Wooley; Dr. Reeves; Chick Ward; Randal Bldg, 1912, UVa; Avazo Lemon, Mamie Anderson, Roanoke college, 1912; Louise and Mable Horton; Henry Earls; Frank Lemon; Strickland Jamison, Frangie Davis. One is a photo of a gravestone with Benjamin Franklin Horton (1844-1921) and Ellen Peterman Horton (1845-1932).
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 3 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-003)
  Includes photos marked #7.H. C.B. 1917, Rogers, Capt. E. 1916; Erskine; Grandad Horton, 1913; Avazo L.; Frank Lemon, Dr. Trimble, Peo. Marsden, UVa Hosp; Corinne Moore; Dr. Sprout; Vallie Russel; C& O Ry, UVa 1914; Elsie Mogs, Heath Moore (Dr. Moore's younger brother--deceased?); Erskine College; Lister, Davis and Ned; Rudolph Moss; Minnie Moore; Ruth Kinser; Katherine and Helen 1940 (Dr. Moore's sisters Katherine and Helen, Helen deceased); Mary Griffith, 1915; Brighten G. N.Y. 1917, S.I. Ferry, N.Y.; Dr. John Beale, Peg Marsden, Dr. Allen VanNess; Home, 1915, 1815 Rorer Ave. Rke. Va.;Uva vs. Penn, 1912 (race); Jacobis; Dr. Brice; Giants 1917; Peg Marsden; Loveline C. Heath M., Myrlte B., Edith M; Dr. Beale, Dr. Trimble; Capt. White; Dr. Bissel; Dr. John Barnwell; Dr. John McGovern; Kinsey; and jacobis.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 4 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-004)
  Long Beach, N.Y., N.Y.H. (New York Hospital) Ward 1917; erskine college, 1916; Barnett; Colombia U., 1917; Peg Marsden; Sid Conger; Mary Douglas; Madison Hall, UVa 1916; Mary D.; Powel House, Roanoke Va.; Frank Horton; Dr. Bornwell; Jean Ashcraft; Gray and Kate Altizer (Kate Peterman Altizer, his grandmother's sister, Gray Altizer is son of Kate A.; Lambeth Field 1917; Dad, 1917; Katherine 1919; Mrs. Douglas; Jack Myers; Forest Hills, Long Island, Homme 1915; Grandpa's Home; Talcott; Corrine Moore, Mothers Home, Horton 1916; Corrine Locket; UVa. Lawn 1916-17, Mother and Katherine; UVa. Hospital; Brighten Beach; McKewing; Mildred Young; Grandpa Horton July 1913; UVa Hosp. 1913; Dr. Williams; Minnie Moore; Union Station, Charlottesville VA. March 5, 1914; Mary D.; Hazel Kinser; Ruth Garret; Monaco 1918; Mrs. Wm. Hackney.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 5 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-005)
  Photos marked Camp Dodge, 1918; Dr. Broders, 1918; Buddy Hackney, 1918; Wilson, N.C.; Katherine M;Dr. Wm. Mayo 1918; Marie Back; Mono Sibeck; Dr. Judd 1918; Camp Dodge Ia. 1918, Eclipse of Sun; Hazel Kinzer.; Ethel Huntimer; Grace Roth; Dr. Pemberton; Des Moines, Iowa, 1918 (parade); Ruth Kinsey; Mary Douglas; Corrine Moore; May clinic 1918; Dr. Verne Hunt; Dr. McGovern; Dr. Henderson; Maggie Sullivan, Dr. Masson; Dr. Graham; Ethel Huntimer; Rochester Minn, my home 1918; Dr. McCarthy; Dorothy Strickland; L.E. Pippin, UVa 1920; Dr. McGoldrick.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 6 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-006)
  Pictures of Europe, Photos marked Pat Marsden; Vincent, Grandad H.; Mother's old home; Retreat Base Hospital, Camp Dodge; Sudie Hackney; Wm. Morris 104 years; Hackney twins; Mildred Young.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 7 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-007)
  Photos of Europe and photos marked U.S. Cemetery 1918, Savenay; no man's land, 1918, Fr.; Horses killed in combat; Dr. Pulford; Edith M.; Savenay Fr.; Barb wire, France 1918; U.S. Army Base Hospital, No. 88 Administration building and troops.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 8 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-008)
  Photos of Europe and photo marked Alice Phillip
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 9 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-009)
  Photos of Europe and photos marked 4 generations: Ray, Wendall, Tom, Horton; Clarkson; Eith M.; Elise Walters; Mildred Young, Thalia Horton, Frank Horon and sons 1919; Lacy Horton 1919; Frank Jr. 1919; Horton Family 1919; Wilson Inaug. 1918; Mrs. Carper; Home in Radford; Mamie Anderson; Elise W.; Mary Griffith; Pippin; Walters; Margaret Motley; Bennets spring; Blake Smiley; Mother; Ashton Barksdale; Mr. and Mrs. Tinsley; Alice Phillip; Fred Easter; W. G. Jones, D. P. Sites; Helen Moore (sister) 1924; White Sulphur springs; Mildred Young; Grove Spitler, Morbonne Muir; Ted Shawn; Tinsley Family; Mary Sue Allison; Ruth St. Dennis; Eva Lavender; Ila Myers; Edith Hale; Mary Lemon; Billie Wayne Dungan.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 10 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-010)
  Photos marked Morris Age 104; Morris 96; Carl, Jack, Myers, Douglas, Fred; Charlie; Grandad H.; Mildred Young; Mary Douglas; Home 1920 J and B Horton; Dorothy Strickland; Mary Douglas; Mother and Mary Lemon; Nonnie Hogo; Katie Noell; Sister Helen; Dr. Spitler; Hosp. Stuart; Hot Springs; Mountain Lake; Edith Walters; Ruth Garrett; Ira Hurt; May Jackson; Moore Graveyard at Beulah church N.C.; D. M. Borum; Grandpa's grave; Dad; G. G. fathers cabin, Dad, Millon, N.C.; McNeal; Mary Wall; Goshen Pass: Mother, Kath, Mary, Dad; Cline Pugh son G. Horton's Sister; Chas Scott and wife Julie; Horton graveyard, Belfast Mills Va.; Grandmother: Paradine wife of Daniel Peterman; Harris W. Coleman: UVa Capt. 1915, Holsinger photo; Dorothy Strickland; Wall Family.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 11 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 04-011)
  Photos marked Grandmother Horton; Mary Wall; Sister Helen H. S. graduation; Rotunda UVa; Mary W. Fannie T.; Warm Springs; Chas and Julia Scott; Joe and Loyd Engleby; Reginald C. Lamb; Walter Hagan; Home; Niece Shirley Smiley and home, July 1927; Babs Grant; Reunion: Horton, Lester, Peterman, Sept 1927; Grandma Horton; Dad, Shirley, Helen, Kath. Edith 1927.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 12 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 05-001)
  Photos of Europe and photos marked on the bridge of Levi (Leviathan); U.S. Cemetery Paris; U.S. Cem. Bony.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 13 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 05-002)
  Photos of Europe.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 14 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 05-003)
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 15 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 05-004)
  Photos of Europe and photos marked Bernita Hammer; Mrs. Spitler; Shirley; Dr. Charley; Dr. Moore with his parents in his garden in Rochester, Minn.; Dr. Will; Mayo clinic 1930; Dr. Sandy Moore; Fred Wiesnek; Julian Howe, Dennis Goodman; Mother; Dorothy Griffith; Margaret McPherson
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 16 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 14 pages (Box-folder 05-005)
  Photos marked Chas. G. Sutherland; Dad, Packard 1931; Home 1931; Mother; Hudson Moore Jr. (Cousin from his father's side); Harry Weber.
- Claude Moore Scrapbook, Folder 17 of 17 N.D., [CA. 1890-1985, bulk from 1910 to 1930], Scrapbook/photograph album: 8 pages (Box-folder 05-006)
  Photos marked Myrtle Bowling; Anna Belle Chafin; Harve Fisher and family; Hazel Kinser Kinzer; Edna Oney; Elsie Moss.